

With over three years of experience in the development of innovative IoT, data and digitalisation solutions, I have extensive know-how. I have mastered classic and agile project management methods, business analysis techniques as well as programming and technology skills to successfully implement

challenging projects. I attach great importance to developing together with

the company in order to realise innovative products using the latest

Michael Bieri

Grotweg 23 2543 Lengnau BE +41 77 413 08 39 michael.bieri@hotmail.com 13.03.1992







Work Experience

07/2024 - 10/2024	Career transition Relocation, travel and continuing education
03/2021 - 06/2024	Product Engineer Electronics LAUFEN Bathrooms AG, Laufen Development and management of soft- and hardware projects with focus on requirement engineering
09/2018 - 02/2021	Junior Project Manager Amstein + Walthert Basel AG, Basel Engineering in building technology/automation
07/2018 - 09/2018	Internship Environmental Engineer Kappeler Infra Consult AG, Laufen
11/2013 - 07/2014	Workshop and Construction Internship F. Hoffmann-La-Roche AG, Basel
11/2010 - 05/2011	Trust Internship TVR Treuhand GmbH, Basel
09/2009 - 10/2009	Bank Internship WIR Bank, Basel

technologies.

Skills

About Me

REQUIREMENT ENGINEERING



ANALYTICAL THINKING



STATISTICS

DATA SCIENCE

DATA ANALYSIS



- Professional Scrum Master II
- Databricks Certified Data Engineer Associate
- Microsoft Fundamentals in Azure, Power Platform, MS365



Education

02/2024 - 08/2024	CAS Data Science Fundamentals Swiss Distance University of Applied Sciences FFHS
09/2019 - 04/2022	MAS Automation Management University of Applied Sciences Northwestern Switzerland FHNW
09/2014 - 05/2018	BSc Energy- and Environment Technology University of Applied Sciences Northwestern Switzerland FHNW
08/2011 - 08/2012	Technical High School Diploma Vocational training center BL
08/2007 - 08/2010	Business Diploma Business school kvBL



Languages

English C1

French B2